<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wyland on Dane&#39;s Blog on Travel and Data</title>
    <link>http://danecollins.github.io/categories/wyland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wyland on Dane&#39;s Blog on Travel and Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://danecollins.github.io/categories/wyland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>San Clemente #2</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/05-sanclemente/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/05-sanclemente/</guid>
      <description>In trying to find walls, it’s sometimes hard to know what reference material to use. All the sources said that Young Gray Whale was no longer at the Ocean Institute but the Wyland site said it was at R. H. Dana Elementary in Dana Point while Wikipedia said it was at Concordia Elementary in San Clemente.
Since Dana Point is on the way to San Clemente (from Laguna Beach) we decided to head there first.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laguna Beach #1 and #12</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/03-lagunabeach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/03-lagunabeach/</guid>
      <description>While traveling to San Diego we wanted to drive through Laguna Beach, as we knew there were several walls we could see there. We hoped these walls would be easy to find, given some of our experiences. Fortunately, they were.
We first found Laguna Coast which is on the side wall of a very cool store that’s definitely worth stopping in. If you’ve never tried to lift a meteorite this is your chance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#100 Beijing, China</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/02-beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/02-beijing/</guid>
      <description>While on my first trip to Beijing I managed to plan a free afternoon and remembered Wyland painted a wall for the Olympics. Searching the Internet in China can be a little bit of a challenge and getting reliable information on the wall was difficult. After some work I found that it was in Chaoyang Park. The park is large and I was not sure I could find it but it was worth a try.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#60 San Francisco, where it all started</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/01-sanfrancisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/01-sanfrancisco/</guid>
      <description>We have enjoyed Wyland&amp;rsquo;s work for many years and had seen some of his walls while traveling. One day while at Pier 39 in San Francisco we were looking at one of these walls and thinking how fun it would be to get our picture in front of some of them.
With this simple first picture started what I&amp;rsquo;m sure will be a long term journey to search for these walls.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
