<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wylands on Travel and Data</title>
    <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wylands on Travel and Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Orleans #69</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/62-neworleans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/62-neworleans/</guid>
      <description>The Blue Whales is the last wall in a long driving trip. We found the wall no problem, but had some trouble trying to find parking as downtown was extremely busy. We got a photo on our first day and then learned we could actually walk from our hotel so we went back the next day and spent more time enjoying the mural. The wall is on the side of the Hilton parking lot near the New Orleans Convention Center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Padre Island #53</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/61-sanpadre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/61-sanpadre/</guid>
      <description> Orcas off the Gulf of Mexico has been recently repainted, unfortunately, not by Wyland. It looks like the original image but it is clear that the style of the new artist varies significantly from Wyland&amp;rsquo;s. The vibrant colors of the new wall and the detail in the scene look great.
South Padre Island Convention Center 7355 Padre Boulevard South Padre Island 265 Feet Long x 25 Feet High Dedicated March 14, 1994 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dallas #82</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/60-dallas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/60-dallas/</guid>
      <description>Ocean Life seems a little misplaced in Dallas, which is a long ways from any ocean. While some walls are hard to find, this one was as easy as they get. It even has a parking lot attached, called the &amp;lsquo;whale lot&amp;rsquo;. After a non-eventful flight from San Jose the wall was only a few minutes away from the airport. There was not much time to linger though as we wanted to get down to San Antonio before nightfall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milwaukee #72</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/59-milwaukee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/59-milwaukee/</guid>
      <description>Whale Commuters has quite the history in Milwaukee . The original wall was on the rounded concrete facade of the former courthouse annex. Some residents loved the wall while others wondered what whales had to do with Milwaukee. The debate did not last long as the wall was destroyed less than 10 years later. A small part of the wall was preserved and hung as a picture on the side of a freeway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Niagara Falls #81</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/58-niagara/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/58-niagara/</guid>
      <description>Since we were in Toronto without a car and wanted to see this wall we could either rent a car or take a bus tour. We chose the latter with hopes that the logistics would work out. The bus stopped on the Canadian side of Niagara and only for 80 minutes. Our issue was that the wall is on the US side. A map told us that it was a walk of about a mile but we knew that we would have to go through Customs both ways and we were unsure how long that would take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto #70</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/57-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/57-toronto/</guid>
      <description> Heavenly Waters is a grand wall although somewhat faded. Since we were in Toronto without a car we had an adventure getting to it but with some walking and the help of the walk-on-walk-off bus we got there. We had a bit of a challenge getting a good picture in the drizzle. On the walk back we dropped in on the NHL Hall of Fame.
Redpath Sugars 95 Queen’s Quay East Toronto 146 Feet Long x 97 Feet High Dedicated September 1, 1997 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Myrtle Beach #49</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/56-myrtlebeach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/56-myrtlebeach/</guid>
      <description> This wall looked great as it has just been repainted, not by Wyland though. The person that did the work did a great job and added some personal touches such as pelicans in the middle of the wall. This was the largest wall we have seen on this trip and was a great way to finish our adventure.
Myrtle Beach Convention Center 2101 N. Oak Street Myrtle Beach 250 Feet Long x 50 Feet High Dedicated September 6, 1993 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilmington, NC #48</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/55-wilmingtonnc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/55-wilmingtonnc/</guid>
      <description>While in Virginia Beach it was time to make a decision about whether we would continue South, into the aftermath of hurricane Florence, or just call it a successful trip and stay in Virginia Beach until the weekend and just fly home from Norfolk. The weather reports from coastal North Carolina still sounded grim with the water levels still increasing. On the other hand, if we did not go now, it was unclear when we would ever be back to see the walls in Wilmington and Myrtle Beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Norfolk #47</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/54-norfolk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/54-norfolk/</guid>
      <description>The wall in Norfolk is in the harbor area. There is a great walkway there that offers a view of the large shipyards across the water and along a World War 2 battleship. The area was pretty quiet with only a few people around. Since it was the convention center area my guess the crowds are based on what is going on at there. “Humpbacks off the Virginia Coast” was easy to find and looks good although part of it is obscured by the construction of the adjacent building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington DC #45</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/53-washington/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/53-washington/</guid>
      <description>It rained quite hard on the way from Baltimore to Washington but by the time we got to the Zoo it had reduced to a drizzle. It was not great Zoo weather and, while not yet lunchtime, the animals has no interest in being out or active. As we usually have a good time at zoos we were a little disappointed but we did get to see “Dolphins-Small Tooth Whales” on the wall of the visitor center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baltimore #46</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/52-baltimore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/52-baltimore/</guid>
      <description>Unlike the West coast, on the East coast, you cat get to three states between lunch and dinner. After our success in Wilmington, we headed off to Baltimore to see “Extinct Atlantic Gray Whales” which while not an original Wyland, it has been repainted by someone else, it still retains most of the Wyland charm. It is in a great location across from the football stadium and I’m sure it is seen by a huge number of people as all Wyland walls should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildwood, NJ #43</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/51-wildwood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/51-wildwood/</guid>
      <description>After the disappointment of the destruction of “East Coast Humpbacks” in Philadelphia, we were doubly disappointed to find that “Humpbacks off the New Jersey Coast” was in the process of being painted over by someone. Especially as Wyland has been rejuvenating so many walls, to have someone else just painting over one of his walls was a little depressing. Given the current state of the repainting, we probably only missed seeing it by a month or two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilmington, DE #44</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/51-wilmingtonde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/51-wilmingtonde/</guid>
      <description>After failed attempts to see a wall in Philadelphia and Wildwood, we finally got to see “Delaware Marine Mammals” in Wilmington. The wall is aged but the only original Wyland wall anywhere around this area. Right as we were finishing our picture the sky opened up and it started pouring rain, so we did not have an opportunity to spend as much time there as we would have liked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York #40</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/50-newyork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/50-newyork/</guid>
      <description>New York is a festive place to visit at Christmas. While the purpose of the visit was to take in the holiday decorations we could not pass up the opportunity to see “Inner City Whales” in the tunnel of the bus station.
Being located in a place dedicated to bus traffic has taken its toll on this mural, as has various construction projects, and we were glad to see it before it deteriorated further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Destin #88</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/49-destin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/49-destin/</guid>
      <description>All of our trips tracking down Walls have been fun and adventurous, but none as much as going to see “Marine Life off the Gulf”.
We had no travel plans to see walls this year but a few weeks ago while at a Wyland show in Carmel we learned that he would be refreshing the wall in Destin, FL. It would be hard to fit the trip into our work schedule but how could we pass up an opportunity to see Wyland actually paint a wall!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco #61</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/48-sanfrancisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/48-sanfrancisco/</guid>
      <description>When our adventure started back in 2010 our first wall was close to home at Pier 39 in San Francisco. There were 2 walls in that area but due to construction around the aquarium it appeared that “Grays off the San Francisco Coast”, wall number 61 was extinct which was very disappointing.
Of course, some days surprise you. While on a trip to San Francisco with my Mom, we’re walking around Pier 39 and walk right by what is clearly a Wyland Wall in really good shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Lauderdale #99</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/47-lauderdale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/47-lauderdale/</guid>
      <description>Wow! What a way to end our Florida trip.
Water for Life is the last wall Wyland painted in the US (and the last wall still in existence) and so much is notable about it. The first being that it’s just a wall. Not part of a building, just a long wall along a walkway.
Second is how the community has embraced it. In our search of walls we spend a lot of time wondering why the wall are where they are and how the community they are in feel about the walls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miami #78</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/46-miami/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/46-miami/</guid>
      <description>Florida Marine Life was painted in 1998 and it makes me wonder how different the area might have been then. Today, there is a light rail train that blocks part of the wall and a huge parking garage that makes it difficult to see the wall unless you’re in the garage. It’s possible that when Wyland painted it neither were there but today the wall is difficult to see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Largo #95</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/45-keylargo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/45-keylargo/</guid>
      <description>It was a long drive from Sarasota to Key Largo but the alligators we saw in the Everglades made the drive worth it. “Keys to the Sea_“_ is a bit different from many of the other walls we’ve seen in that the mural is on all 4 sides of the building. It also contains a scuba diver which is very unusual. Maybe because the mural is on the walls of a dive shop or because Wyland is such an avid diver himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key West #52</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/44-keywest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/44-keywest/</guid>
      <description>Getting to Key West was a scenic drive but took longer than we expected. Finding the wall took a bit more time. There are times when we walk up to walls and are awed by them and times when we walk up and wonder just what the owners are doing. Unfortunately Florida’s Living Reef was the latter.
Looking at what is left of the wall, you get the feeling that this was a spectacular mural when Wyland painted it but now, as the building is being turned into a brew pub, it’s being chopped up and covered up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon Key #27</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/43-marathoncrane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/43-marathoncrane/</guid>
      <description>This wall is directly across the street from the wall in the KMart but definitely does not have the grandeur of Florida’s Radiant Reef. It appears that some modifications have taken place to the building the wall is on so that now the wall is in separate sections. This lead to us only being able to get our picture in front of part of the wall but below are some pictures of other sections of the wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon Key #87</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/42-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/42-marathon/</guid>
      <description>As I’ve mentioned before, it is hard to understand how Wyland selects the locations for his walls. I think that Florida’s Radiant Reef is my favorite wall to date and it is on the wall of a KMart! This wall has some of everything in it and is in great shape. It is big and visible from the main road so I’m sure a ton of people get to see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homosassa Springs #86</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/40-homosassa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/40-homosassa/</guid>
      <description>Manatee Sanctuary is at the Visitor Center for the Homosassa Springs Wildlife Park. This is right on Hwy 19 and about one mile from the entrance to the Park itself. The wall is outside of the park so you don’t have to pay admission to see it.
After seeing two walls that were more painting than mural it was nice to see a mural again. This one is in the harsh sunlight but is still in good shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orlando Renaissance Hotel #11</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/39-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/39-orlando/</guid>
      <description>When walls are outdoors I can often use Google Street View to track them down and make sure they are still there but when they are in airports and hotels it is more of a ‘show up and see’ adventure as it was for First Born at the Renaissance. In this case it was right in the hotel lobby and could not have been easier to find. I really like the simplicity of First Born.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarasota&#39;s Mote Marine Lab #51</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/41-sarasota/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/41-sarasota/</guid>
      <description>After a fun day of driving down all the beaches from Clearwater to Sarasota we arrived at the Mote aquarium. We were close but not quite there as the Marine lab is across the street. Not only did we get to see Florida’s Dolphins but we had a sweet volunteer tell us about all the turtles they are saving. We even got to see one that is recovering from being struck from a propeller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orlando Airport #10</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/38-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/38-orlando/</guid>
      <description>One of the benefits of our search for Wyland murals is that it takes us places we would not normally go. In this case, we headed to the last state that has many walls we have not seen so, we find ourselves in Florida. After spending the weekend in Minneapolis in 10 degree weather, the Florida climate makes us feel right at home.
Florida is a state with 11 walls so it took some planning to figure out how to see as many as possible in one trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Wyland in Carmel</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/withwyland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/withwyland/</guid>
      <description>This post does not belong in this series as it is not about finding a wall but, for us it is so memorable. At an event at the Wyland Gallery in Carmel, we were able to meet Wyland. Even more exciting was watching him paint several different pieces from start to finish. His ability to create stunning images in a short amount of time is truly amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Valley, Minnesota Zoo #71</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/37-applevalley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/37-applevalley/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you find a wall where you don’t expect to see one. We went to Minneapolis to visit family last week. When I think of Minnesota, oceans and whales are not the first thing that comes to mind but I figured it would not hurt to check the list of walls and sure enough there was one at the Zoo. It is always much harder to research a wall that is not out in public so you’re never really sure if it is going to be there but we were able to find Our Ocean Family and were surprised by how good a shape it is in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honolulu #85</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/34-honolulu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/34-honolulu/</guid>
      <description>On the way from the airport to the hotel, from highway H1, we got to see “New Millenium” and while we knew we would have to come back to it to get our picture, as we drove by, I noticed there was another mural on the other side of the building. I was completely confused by that as there was no listing for another wall at that location. Anytime we’ve seen 2 walls on the same building they have had unique numbers on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea Life Park Oahu #15</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/33-sealifepark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/33-sealifepark/</guid>
      <description>I am always wary of walls that are in locations where you have to pay to get in. After finding so many extinct walls I was concerned about paying admission to Sea Life Park just to see Dolphins off Makapuu Point. We managed to find a way around that though. We signed up to go swim with the dolphins which was a great adventure and got us into the park so we were able to see the wall also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honolulu #6*</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/35-honolulu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/35-honolulu/</guid>
      <description>After getting home I knew I had to do more research into this wall. Reading between the lines of the Wikipedia page I figured out that this wall is a reproduction of wall #6, “Hawaiian Humpbacks”, which was previously destroyed. It’s not exactly the same as the original but it is very close and it is part of the Wyland collection. A while later the Wyland Foundation posted some clarifying information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honolulu #89</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/36-honolulu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/36-honolulu/</guid>
      <description>I had some concern about finding Humpback Realm. It’s listed as being at “Navy Exchange” which make it seem like it was on a military facility but the only Navy Exchange I could find on the internet was a shopping mall. I was a little doubtful that this was what we were looking for; but since that is all I could find, I figured it was worth giving it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waikiki #67</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/32-waikiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/32-waikiki/</guid>
      <description>I had done a little less research on the walls in Honolulu than those on Kauai but figured I had a good idea where to start. We saw the first wall on the way to the hotel from the airport although we will need to go back there to get our picture in front of it.
For Earth Day Hawaii though, we could just walk to it from our hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaui&#39;a #28 and #29</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/30-kauai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/30-kauai/</guid>
      <description>We have been to Kaua’i once before but Alex was 7 then and it was long before we were searching for Wyland walls. For his graduation from USC we wanted to take him and Kristie somewhere and given how much he has always liked Hawaii it seemed like a great place to go. It seemed natural to make sure we saw the wall here on this trip but in planning I ran into some trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newport #59</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/29-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/29-newport/</guid>
      <description>After our trip to Seattle, Victoria and Vancouver we had just about exhausted the west coast and had only one wall remaining. We had been wanting to visit Portland anyway so we took a few days and saw Portland with a quick day trip down to Newport. We love the aquarium in Newport but for this trip we had a goal of seeing “Gray Whales off Oregon Coast”. Many of the walls in Newport are adorned with murals but none as spectacular as this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver #56</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/26-vancouver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/26-vancouver/</guid>
      <description>After the disappointment on Melville Street I was a little concerned. Of the last 4 walls we’ve visited, 3 were extinct and 1 was so covered up by new construction you can barely see it. The wall on Grandville was interesting because it was painted in only 12 hours as a continuation of the mural at the aquarium. In trying to find the wall on Google Maps it was very difficult to get an angle where I could see the wall so we we’re unsure where it should be, even though we had an address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver Aquarium #55</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/28-vancouveraquarium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/28-vancouveraquarium/</guid>
      <description>After getting back from White Rock we thought we would do some sight-seeing on the hop-on hop-off bus but it was done for the day. Being too early for dinner we thought we might as well go to Stanley (of Stanley Cup fame) Park to the aquarium to see Orcas A-30 Subpod. The first thing that struck us regarding the aquarium was all the construction. As we’ve learned, new construction is rarely a good thing in regards to us finding intact murals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Rock #4</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/27-whiterock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/27-whiterock/</guid>
      <description>After our success on the Grandville bridge we needed to figure out how to get to White Rock, a suburb of Vancouver. We thought of renting a car and driving down but renting a car is not always easy. We got lucky that Hertz was out of cars and the counter person suggested we take the SkyTrain and a bus to get there. She had a friend in White Rock and knew exactly how to get there on public transportation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver #8</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/25-vancouver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/25-vancouver/</guid>
      <description>Another ferry ride, which actually turned out to be more of a bus ride than a ferry ride, from Victoria to Vancouver and we were ready to head to another wall. From the Google street view images I could tell that Orcas was not intact because some housing had been built against it which covered some of it. When we got there we saw that the bottom of the mural was completely gone and only the top part, missing all of the whales, was left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Victoria #13</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/24-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/24-victoria/</guid>
      <description>After a ferry ride from Seattle to Victoria we decided to head over to the other end of downtown Victoria to see A-5 Pod. This was a pod that lived, and maybe still does, off Vancouver Island and this wall was painted with the individual features of the whales in that pod. The deterioration of the wall is quite apparent in the picture the building is undergoing renovation so it’s a good thing we saw this now as it may not be around for much longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle #57 and #58 - RIP</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/23-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/23-seattle/</guid>
      <description>As the sun started to set on Pike Place Market, I thought the setting sun would be a good backdrop to seeing Leap of Faith, Wyland’s first mural using warm colors. As a bonus we could also see Orcas off the San Juan Islands on the opposite side of the same building which depicts the J-1 pod Wyland visited with during his stay in Seattle.
The hotel was easy to find but unfortunately there were no murals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tacoma #21</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/22-tacoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/22-tacoma/</guid>
      <description>On our trip to Seattle we flew into SeaTac which made it convenient to head straight to Tacoma to see Washington Orcas which turned out to be very easy to find. Given the wet weather here I was unsure how well it would hold up and while it is a little faded it is holding up well. This wall depicts a pod of whales that resides near Tacoma.
Across the parking lot is a small insurance office with the best view in Tacoma!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hollywood #63</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/21-hollywood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/21-hollywood/</guid>
      <description>After the disappointment in Santa Monica and Chicago we were looking forward to finding wall that was intact. On a trip to LA for a wedding, we got there a few hours early which gave us an opportunity to run up to Hollywood. Life Size Blue Whales turned out to be much easier to find. It is on a the wall of a building, on the outside of the Paramount complex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa Monica #79</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/20-santamonica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/20-santamonica/</guid>
      <description>Our company Christmas party was in Santa Monica and since we needed to spend the night it gave us a great opportunity to visit “Santa Monica’s Marine Life” on the Pier. With a clear and crisp morning we took a nice walk to the pier and walked the entire pier looking for the mural but to no avail. We asked at the police station on the pier but they could not help us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago #73</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/19-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/19-chicago/</guid>
      <description>We went to spend the weekend in Chicago. It was our first time there and we had a great time. When it came time to look for the The Windy Whales we were not sure what we would find. Wikipedia lists the wall as extinct. We had no trouble finding the Inter-Continental hotel but when we got there we found that they had built an apartment building covering most of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portland #36</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/18-portland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/18-portland/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things we noticed walking by Whales off the Coast of Maine was the sea turtle which we saw for the first time. This wall is in a great spot as you can walk right along it for the full length of the pier.
The sun has taken it’s toll on this wall with the images showing significant fading but it’s definitely worth seeing.
Like the wall in New Bedford this wall let’s you see several different types of whales as well as dolphins all on one wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portsmouth #37</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/17-portsmouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/17-portsmouth/</guid>
      <description>Looking at the online pictures of Isle of Shoals Humpbacks it looks wonderful and we were really looking forward to seeing it. Upon getting there though it was sad to see the shape the wall is in.
It’s clear this was a great wall when it was created but it has not aged well with a lot of the paint missing. An additional disappointment was seeing graffiti on the wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Bedford #93</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/16-newbedford/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/16-newbedford/</guid>
      <description>I always wonder how Wyland selected the locations for his walls. Some just seem too secluded for how great they are but the Great Whales of New Bedford is not one of those. As you drive in to New Bedford you just can’t miss the walls of the Marine Terminal with whales covering all sides of the building. Given the significance of whales to New Bedford this wall seems so at home here and being one of the newer walls is in such great shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portsmouth #37</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/14-portsmouth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/14-portsmouth/</guid>
      <description>I always wonder how Wyland selected the locations for his walls. Some just seem too secluded for how great they are but the Great Whales of New Bedford is not one of those. As you drive in to New Bedford you just can’t miss the walls of the Marine Terminal with whales covering all sides of the building. Given the significance of whales to New Bedford this wall seems so at home here and being one of the newer walls is in such great shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New London #41</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/15-newlondon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/15-newlondon/</guid>
      <description>Driving into New London, CT while staring at the iPhone for directions and looking for street signs we managed to drive right past The Great Sperm Whales without seeing it which is pretty hard as it’s right on the main street. The wall is in great shape and is one of the most approachable walls we’ve seen. The wall is big and it was pretty hard to get all of it in a picture so here is part of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salt Lake City #80</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/13-saltlake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/13-saltlake/</guid>
      <description>When we first started looking at the location of all the walls and I saw Salt Lake City I figured it would be a long time before we got to that one. Goes to show how life can be unpredictable.
Just 5 months after we started this adventure we find ourselves moving to Boulder and driving right through Salt Lake City on our way there. With just a little planning it was easy to get there during the day when we could see World of Ocean Life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Beach #33</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/11-longbeach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/11-longbeach/</guid>
      <description>We found ourselves quite lucky when we got to the Long Beach Convention Center to find that there was no conference. The place was deserted; this made it quite easy for us to go around the entire conference center and see the entire wall. If you go to the hotel next to the convention center you can go up to the 17th floor and from the hallway windows you can get a great overall view of the painting but unfortunately it’s still not high enough to be able to see the painting on the roof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redondo Beach #31</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/12-redondobeach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/12-redondobeach/</guid>
      <description>We had actually seen Gray Whale Migration once before. One of the few walls we were not seeing for the first time but it’s just as impressive the second time around.
Seeing a beautiful wall like this where the owners let so much vegetation cover it up makes me wonder why they wanted it. It would be so easy to keep it clear. This wall contains his first blue whale on a whaling wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laguna Beach #68</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/10-lagunabeach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/10-lagunabeach/</guid>
      <description>The benefit of heading to Laguna Beach a second time is that we knew exactly where to go. I was worried that it would be hard to get a picture of both us and Pacific Realm since it is on the ceiling but that turned out not to be too hard.
Like all of the walls there is just no way to really do justice to them in pictures as they cover so much area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Diego #64</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/09-sandiego/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/09-sandiego/</guid>
      <description>After chasing down pictures of yachts we knew the next wall would be easier to find and take a picture of since it would not be moving. We just saw it a little earlier than expected.
We started Father’s day with a Segway tour of San Diego which was a ton of fun. While on the tour it seemed some of the buildings were familiar. I had not been to that part of town before but I did a lot of looking around in Google street view looking for the wall and while we waited at a stop light I turned to see Life Size Blue Whales right there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belmont Park #16</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/06-belmontpark/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/06-belmontpark/</guid>
      <description>After the uncertainty in looking for #2 we felt much more certain about finding Orcas off Point Loma as we knew it was at Belmont Park and at an indoor pool. The big questions were whether we would have to pay to get into the park and whether there was any way to get inside the pool.
It turns out, unlike Disneyland or Sea World which requires everyone to pay to get in, Belmont Park has no entrance fee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Del Mar Fairgrounds #94</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/07-delmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/07-delmar/</guid>
      <description>Ride the Tide at the Del Mar fairgrounds is visible from the 5 freeway so it’s not hard to find. Unfortunately, the time we could visit it turned out to be when the fair was going on which made it considerable harder to get to it. We did manage to find a drop-off spot at the fairgrounds and were able to get a picture from a distance but could not get as close as we would have liked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harbor Island #83</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/08-harborisland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/08-harborisland/</guid>
      <description>When I first started researching Race to Save the Ocean I actually put it into the extinct category because I figured a privately owned racing yacht is not something you could get access to, if it even still existed. I was wrong. While talking to my Dad I learned that not only did the yacht still exist, but that it was used as a charter boat sailing out of San Diego.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Clemente #2</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/05-sanclemente/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/05-sanclemente/</guid>
      <description>In trying to find walls, it’s sometimes hard to know what reference material to use. All the sources said that Young Gray Whale was no longer at the Ocean Institute but the Wyland site said it was at R. H. Dana Elementary in Dana Point while Wikipedia said it was at Concordia Elementary in San Clemente.
Since Dana Point is on the way to San Clemente (from Laguna Beach) we decided to head there first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laguna Beach #1 and #12</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/03-lagunabeach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/03-lagunabeach/</guid>
      <description>While traveling to San Diego we wanted to drive through Laguna Beach, as we knew there were several walls we could see there. We hoped these walls would be easy to find, given some of our experiences. Fortunately, they were.
We first found Laguna Coast (wall #12) which is on the side wall of a very cool store that’s definitely worth stopping in. If you’ve never tried to lift a meteorite this is your chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#100 Beijing, China</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/02-beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/02-beijing/</guid>
      <description>While on my first trip to Beijing I managed to plan a free afternoon and remembered Wyland painted a wall for the Olympics. Searching the Internet in China can be a little bit of a challenge and getting reliable information on the wall was difficult. After some work I found that it was in Chaoyang Park. The park is large and I was not sure I could find it but it was worth a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#60 San Francisco, where it all started</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/01-sanfrancisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/wyland/01-sanfrancisco/</guid>
      <description>We have enjoyed Wyland&amp;rsquo;s work for many years and had seen some of his walls while traveling. One day while at Pier 39 in San Francisco we were looking at one of these walls and thinking how fun it would be to get our picture in front of some of them.
With this simple first picture started what I&amp;rsquo;m sure will be a long term journey to search for these walls.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
