<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>StatePark on Dane&#39;s Blog on Travel and Data</title>
    <link>http://danecollins.github.io/tags/statepark/</link>
    <description>Recent content in StatePark on Dane&#39;s Blog on Travel and Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://danecollins.github.io/tags/statepark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>McArthur - Burney Falls State Park</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/mcarthur/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/mcarthur/</guid>
      <description>The waterfall through the basalt cliff is spectacular. We got to see it late in the afternoon and the sun was not at the best angle but this is a place that is worth going to more than once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpinteria State Park: A Beachside Haven</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/carpinteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/carpinteria/</guid>
      <description>Located just south of Santa Barbara, Carpinteria State Park Campground is a perfect destination for anyone looking for a beachside retreat that also offers access to nearby amenities. With campsites situated right on the beach, some with hookups, visitors can enjoy stunning views of the Pacific Ocean and a range of outdoor activities.
One of the standout features of this campground is its proximity to Carpinteria’s charming downtown area, where visitors can find a variety of restaurants and shops within easy walking distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Elijo State Beach and Campground</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/san-elijo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/san-elijo/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of campgrounds along the southern California coast but many of them are isolated. From San Elijo you can walk to a few restaurants and directly access the walking path. The campground is on a bluff rather than right on the beach but the views are worth it.
The best sites are 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 31, 33, 35, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41, 43, 45, 47, 49, 59, 60, 146, 147, 148, 150, 151, 152, 153, 155, 162, 163, 165, 168.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garrapata State Park: Sample the Big Sur Coast</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/garrapata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/garrapata/</guid>
      <description>Just south of Carmel there are many options for viewing the Big Sur coast. My favorite one is at Garrapata State Park. Its coastal trails are easy to access, easy to hike and have great views of the coast. You can also get to the beach where you can see some interesting rock formations in the bluffs.
Nestled just south of the quaint town of Carmel lies a stretch of California&amp;rsquo;s most iconic coastline – Big Sur.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
