<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Travel and Data</title>
    <link>http://danecollins.github.io/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Travel and Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://danecollins.github.io/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lake Nacimiento during the poppy bloom</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/nacimiento/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/nacimiento/</guid>
      <description>With the big rainfalls we have had this year we knew that there would be wildflowers. While spending a few days in Paso Robles we thought we would explore a little and ended up heading over to Lake Nacimiento. It was definitely worth the trip as the wild flowers were out in force.
While the wild flowers were the highlight of the trip on our way back to the freeway I spotted this great folded sandstone which was completely unexpected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huge Crystals in Granite at Monastery Beach</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/monastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/monastery/</guid>
      <description>Cora and I love climbing around the rocks at Monastery Beach in Carmel. We get to see granite in a lot of places in California but it is rare than you can see it layered like this, especially in such as accessible place. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever heading to Big Sur it is worth stopping here to walk around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rocks Across the Bay</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/marin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/marin/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d read about folded radiolarian chert getting pushed up onto land and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen pictures but I have to say the pictures do not do it justice. Driving down Conzelman Road in Sausalito you can get up close and it is quite a sight.
While you&amp;rsquo;re in the area, it is worth going to Black Sands Beach to see the black sand, it is quite striking, and the pillow basalt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>McArthur - Burney Falls State Park</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/mcarthur/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/mcarthur/</guid>
      <description>The waterfall through the basalt cliff is spectacular. We got to see it late in the afternoon and the sun was not at the best angle but this is a place that is worth going to more than once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cycling from Carpinteria to Ventura</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/ventura_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/ventura_path/</guid>
      <description>There is a path that goes from Rincon Point (with a little effort you can actually start from Carpinteria State Park) all the way to Marina Park in Ventura. Much of the trail is right along the ocean and the view is wonderful. It&amp;rsquo;s an easy ride that is well worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The wonders of the Petrified Forest National Park</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/petrified-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/petrified-forest/</guid>
      <description>Initially uncertain about what to expect, our visit to the Petrified Forest National Park was a delightful revelation. This expansive park offers more than just a casual glimpse into ancient geology; it provides a captivating landscape filled with petrified wood.
Why the Petrified Forest is Worth the Visit
Ample Space to Roam: One of the first things you&amp;rsquo;ll notice is the park&amp;rsquo;s sheer size, allowing you to wander freely and take in the sights of petrified wood scattered all around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpinteria State Park: A Beachside Haven</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/carpinteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/carpinteria/</guid>
      <description>Located just south of Santa Barbara, Carpinteria State Park Campground is a perfect destination for anyone looking for a beachside retreat that also offers access to nearby amenities. With campsites situated right on the beach, some with hookups, visitors can enjoy stunning views of the Pacific Ocean and a range of outdoor activities.
One of the standout features of this campground is its proximity to Carpinteria’s charming downtown area, where visitors can find a variety of restaurants and shops within easy walking distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laguna Dog Park: San Luis Opisbo</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/laguna-dog-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/laguna-dog-park/</guid>
      <description>We end up driving down 101 frequently, and after a few hours it is nice to have a place that Cora can run around. This park is one of Cora’s favorite places. There is a park and a frisbee golf course so there is a large area to run around. It&amp;rsquo;s close to the freeway so it is easy to get to and it is close to downtown SLO if it is time to eat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Rock Canyon State Park</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/redrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/redrock/</guid>
      <description>There are parks that are easy to get to and that are in places where you&amp;rsquo;re likely to go so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to drop in on a trip. This is not one of them. It&amp;rsquo;s East of Bakersfield and North of Lancaster and is really a destination in itself. If you make the trip though you are rewarded by some geology you don&amp;rsquo;t often get to see.
Cora really enjoyed running around all the rocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Elijo State Beach and Campground</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/san-elijo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/san-elijo/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of campgrounds along the southern California coast but many of them are isolated. From San Elijo you can walk to a few restaurants and directly access the walking path. The campground is on a bluff rather than right on the beach but the views are worth it.
The best sites are 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 31, 33, 35, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41, 43, 45, 47, 49, 59, 60, 146, 147, 148, 150, 151, 152, 153, 155, 162, 163, 165, 168.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garrapata State Park: Sample the Big Sur Coast</title>
      <link>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/garrapata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danecollins.github.io/travel/garrapata/</guid>
      <description>Just south of Carmel there are many options for viewing the Big Sur coast. My favorite one is at Garrapata State Park. Its coastal trails are easy to access, easy to hike and have great views of the coast. You can also get to the beach where you can see some interesting rock formations in the bluffs.
Nestled just south of the quaint town of Carmel lies a stretch of California&amp;rsquo;s most iconic coastline – Big Sur.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
